Are you ready, kids?
孩子们，你们准备好了吗？
Aye, aye, Captain!
是啊是啊，队长！
I can't hear you.
我听不到你说话。
Aye, aye, Captain!
是啊是啊，队长！
♪ Oh...
♪ 哦...
♪ Who lives in a pineapple
under the sea? ♪
♪ 谁住在菠萝里
在海底？ ♪
♪ SpongeBob SquarePants! ♪
♪ 海绵宝宝！ ♪
♪ Absorbent and yellow
and porous is he. ♪
♪ 吸水性和黄色
他是多孔的。 ♪
♪ SpongeBob SquarePants! ♪
♪ 海绵宝宝！ ♪
♪ If nautical nonsense be
something you wish... ♪
♪ 如果航海方面的废话是
你想要的东西...♪
♪ SpongeBob SquarePants! ♪
♪ 海绵宝宝！ ♪
♪ Then drop on the deck
and flop like a fish. ♪
♪ 然后落在甲板上
然后像鱼一样扑通扑通。 ♪
♪ SpongeBob SquarePants! ♪
♪ 海绵宝宝！ ♪
♪ Ready?
SpongeBob SquarePants! ♪
♪ 准备好了吗？
海绵宝宝！ ♪
♪ SpongeBob SquarePants!
♪ 海绵宝宝！
Captioning sponsored by THE
U.S. DEPARTMENT OF EDUCATION
字幕由 THE 赞助
美国教育部
and NICKELODEON
和尼克国际儿童频道
Ah, the Krusty Krab.
啊，蟹堡王。
Through these doors pass all
the many kinds of undersea life.
通过这些门，所有的
多种海底生物。
Through the double doors!
穿过双门！
Away!
离开！
Also these guys.
还有这些家伙。
I told you I'm not
hungry, Mermaidman.
我告诉过你我不是
饿了，美人鱼。
Nonsense, Barnacleboy.
胡说八道，藤壶男孩。
We've got to keep up
our strength
我们必须跟上
我们的力量
for the fight against evil!
为了对抗邪恶！
What a dive.
真是一次潜水。
To the register!
到登记处！
Away!
离开！
Can I help you?
我可以帮你吗？
A double Krabby Patty
and coral bits for me
双层蟹肉饼
和我的珊瑚碎片
and a Silly Meal for the lad.
还为这小伙子准备了一顿傻饭。
Uh, it's not for the toy,
I just, uh...
呃，这不是为了玩具，
我只是，呃...
I gotta fit
in the tights, you know?
我必须适应
穿紧身衣，你知道吗？
Whatever.
任何。
Five dollars, please.
请五美元。
You got it, Bucky.
你明白了，巴基。
Will this cover it?
这个会覆盖吗？
No.
不。
Listen, Big Nose.
听着，大鼻子。
That guy's been saving your butt
那家伙一直在拯救你的屁股
since before you were born.
从你出生之前开始。
Don't you got
a Living Legend
discount or something?
难道你没有
活着的传奇
折扣什么的？
This is a restaurant,
not a lending library.
这是一家餐厅，
不是借阅图书馆。
And who're you calling
Big Nose, Big Nose?
你在给谁打电话
大鼻子，大鼻子？
Hmm.
唔。
Mm-hmm.
Hmm.
嗯嗯。
唔。
Hmm.
The next time danger threatens,
下次当危险来临的时候，
don't expect any help from us.
不要指望我们提供任何帮助。
I'm shaking.
我在发抖。
Hmm... Mermaidman
and Barnacleboy.
嗯……美人鱼
和藤壶男孩。
Mermaidman and Barnacleboy!
美人鱼和藤壶男孩！
Must... get...
autograph!
必须……得到……
签名！
Ha!
哈!
Yah!
啊！
If you want to grow up
strong like me,
如果你想长大
像我一样坚强
you gotta make room for seconds.
你得腾出几秒钟的空间。
Here comes our waiter.
我们的服务员来了。
Auto... graph...!
自动...图表...！
Holy sea cow,
it's that sponge kid.
圣海牛，
就是那个海绵宝宝。
Quick lad!
快点小伙子！
To the invisible boat mobile.
向隐形船移动。
Away!
离开！
Where'd we park?
我们把车停在哪里？
Uh...
呃...
Can I have your autograph?
我可以要你的签名吗？
Can I have your...?
我可以要你的...吗？
They're gone.
他们走了。
Mermaidman's belt!
美人鱼腰带！
Wait!
等待！
We'll find it with
the invisible boat alarm!
我们会找到它
隐形船警报器！
There she is!
她在那儿！
Yeow!
哟！
I told you we should've
got the automatic.
我告诉过你我们应该
拿到了自动的。
Hey guys, wait up!
嘿伙计们，等等！
I've got something for you.
我有东西给你。
Floor it!
地板吧！
You forgot your belt!
你忘记带腰带了！
You forgot...
你忘了...
Mermaidman's
secret utility belt.
美人鱼的
秘密实用腰带。
The emblem of
submersible justice.
会徽
潜入正义。
For 65 years, this belt
has helped prevent
65 年来，这条腰带
有助于防止
the fall of nations.
国家的衰落。
And pants.
还有裤子。
I can't believe I'm actually
holding it in my hands.
我不敢相信我真的是
把它握在我手里。
Well, I guess
I should return it.
嗯，我猜
我应该归还它。
Or not.
或不。
I could just hold on to it
until after work.
我可以坚持下去
直到下班后。
All alone
with Mermaidman's belt.
独自一人
与美人鱼的腰带。
I wonder what this button does.
我想知道这个按钮有什么作用。
Whoa...
哇...
The small ray.
小射线。
Here's your shake, sir.
这是您的奶昔，先生。
Hmm.
唔。
There you go.
就这样吧。
Come again, sir.
再来吧，先生。
SpongeBob!
海绵宝宝！
What's going on in here?
这里发生了什么事？
Huh?
啊？
Why is everything all tiny?
为什么一切都那么小？
I don't know.
我不知道。
What have you got?
你有什么？
Nothing.
没有什么。
No, really.
不，真的。
Nothing!
没有什么！
Let's see it!
让我们看看吧！
No, no!
不，不！
Is that Mermaidman's belt?
这是美人鱼的腰带吗？
Yes.
是的。
Wow!
哇！
I can't believe
he'd lend it to you.
我不敢相信
他会把它借给你。
Me, uh, either.
我，呃，也是。
He didn't lend it
to you, did he?
他没借
对你来说，是吗？
Please don't tell.
请不要告诉。
You stoleit.
你偷了。
Please don't tell!
请不要告诉！
Oh, I'm telling.
哦，我告诉你。
If Mermaidman finds out,
如果美人鱼发现了
he'll kick me out
of his fan club for sure!
他会把我踢出去
当然是他的粉丝俱乐部！
Please don't tell!
请不要告诉！
Uh-oh!
呃-哦！
There's the phone.
电话在那儿。
Don't!
不！
I'm walking
我正在走路
towards the phone.
走向电话。
No!
不！
I'm getting closer
我越来越近了
to the phone.
到电话。
Don't!
不！
And now for the moment
现在暂时
we've all been waiting for.
我们都在等待。
I'm begging you!
我求求你了！
Hello.
你好。
I'd like to speak to Mer...
我想和梅尔谈谈...
What did... Ow!
做了什么……哎呀！
Hello? Hello?
你好？你好？
What did you do to me?!
你对我做了什么？！
I'm sorry,
but you made me do it!
对不起，
但你让我这么做了！
SpongeBob, if you don't return
me to normal size right now,
海绵宝宝，如果你不回来
我现在的尺寸是正常的
you are going to be
你将会成为
in really big trouble.
真的遇到大麻烦了。
Uh... uh... okay.
呃……呃……好吧。
I said now!
我说现在！
Uh...
呃...
Uh... uh...
呃……呃……
Uh...
呃...
Do you hear me?!
你听到我说话了吗？
Holy fish paste!
圣鱼酱！
Get it off me!
把它从我身上拿开！
Don't you know
how to work that thing?
你不知道吗
怎么做那个东西？
Uh, I can do it!
嗯，我能做到！
Stop!
停止！
I've got an idea.
我有一个主意。
Let's call Mermaidman and...
我们就叫美人鱼吧...
No!
不！
I can't let you do that!
我不能让你这么做！
But there must be
someone else who
can help.
但一定有
其他人
可以提供帮助。
Someone smart and wise
一个聪明又睿智的人
with years of life experience.
凭借多年的生活经验。
Patrick!
帕特里克！
Patrick, Patrick!
帕特里克，帕特里克！
Oh, hi, SpongeBob!
哦，嗨，海绵宝宝！
I was at work
我当时在工作
and Mermaidman
and Barnacleboy came,
和美人鱼
藤壶男孩来了，
and I got this belt and look!
我拿到了这条腰带，看看！
A Squidward action figure!
章鱼哥可动人偶！
Let me play with him!
让我陪他玩吧！
No, Patrick!
不，帕特里克！
Fighter pilot!
战斗机飞行员！
Dive bomb!
俯冲炸弹！
Patrick!
帕特里克！
And then a giant fist!
然后是一个巨大的拳头！
Patrick, no!
帕特里克，不！
That's not an action figure,
这不是一个动作人物，
that's the real Squidward.
这才是真正的章鱼哥。
I shrunk him by accident.
我不小心把他缩小了。
Oh.
哦。
And then comes a giant...
然后来了一个巨人……
Wait, you don't understand!
等等，你不明白！
This is serious!
这很严重！
I don't know how
to un-shrink him.
我不知道怎么办
来取消他的缩小。
He could be stuck like this
他可能会被困成这样
for the rest of his life.
他的余生。
Oh, don't worry about it.
哦，别担心。
He'll find love one day.
总有一天他会找到爱情。
You think so?
你这么认为吗？
Sure, but it'll be
当然可以，但是会是
with someone his own size.
和一个和他体型一样大的人。
Like this pickle!
比如这个泡菜！
See?
看？
They like each other!
他们互相喜欢！
No, no, no, no.
不，不，不，不。
Oh, if only I knew
how to work this thing.
哦，如果我知道就好了
如何操作这个东西。
Let me take a look at it.
让我看一下。
Hmm...
唔...
You know what the problem is?
你知道问题是什么吗？
What?
什么？
You got it set to "M", for mini.
你把它设置为“M”，代表迷你。
When it should be set
to "W", for "wumbo."
何时应该设置
到“W”，代表“wumbo”。
Patrick, I don't think
"wumbo" is a real word.
帕特里克，我不认为
“wumbo”是一个真实的词。
Come on.
快点。
You know:
你知道：
I wumbo, you wumbo,
he-she-me wumbo.
我wumbo，你wumbo，
他-她-我wumbo。
Wumbo, wumboing...
呜呜呜呜呜……
I wonder if a fall
from this height
我想知道是否跌倒
从这个高度
would be enough to kill me.
就足以杀了我。
Wumbology?
乌姆博学？
The study of wumbo?
温博的研究？
It's first grade, SpongeBob!
海绵宝宝，一年级了！
Patrick, I'm sorry
I doubted you.
帕特里克，对不起
我怀疑你。
Well, all right, then.
好吧，那么。
Let 'er rip!
让我们撕裂吧！
It worked!
成功了！
Oh, no!
哦，不！
Look!
看！
SpongeBob's giant!
海绵宝宝的巨人！
Can I be giant next?
下一个我可以成为巨人吗？
Patrick, I'm not giant.
帕特里克，我不是巨人。
You've shrunk, too!
你也变小了！
You're kidding!
你开玩笑吧！
Good thing I've still
got this pickle!
还好我还有
得到这个泡菜了！
Hey, now will you
take us to Mermaidman?!
嘿，现在你会吗
带我们去看美人鱼？！
No!
不！
He can never find out!
他永远也查不出！
But I'll think of something.
但我会想到一些事情。
I promise.
我保证。
Until then,
you'll be safe in this jar.
直到那时，
你在这个罐子里会很安全。
You know what's funny?
你知道什么好笑吗？
My pickle started out in a jar,
我的泡菜是从罐子里开始的，
and now it's in one again.
现在又合二为一了。
Huh, it's like
a pun or something.
呵呵，就像是
双关语什么的。
It's only two people.
只有两个人。
No big deal.
没什么大不了的。
Nobody else saw it.
没有其他人看到它。
Howdy, SpongeBob!
你好，海绵宝宝！
Sandy!
沙！
What did you...
For cryin'...
你做了什么...
为了哭...
What did ya'll do to me?
你要对我做什么？
I'm sorry, Sandy!
对不起，桑迪！
Mermaidman came in, and...
美人鱼进来了，然后……
Hey, SpongeBob...
嘿，海绵宝宝...
Hey, SpongeBob?
嘿，海绵宝宝？
Hi, SpongeBob.
嗨，海绵宝宝。
Hello, SpongeBob.
你好，海绵宝宝。
Whoo!
呼！
Sponge-Dude!
海绵哥们！
Whew! I'm gonna
have to get a bigger jar.
哇！我要
必须买一个更大的罐子。
SpongeBob, will you
just face facts?
海绵宝宝，你愿意吗
只面对事实？
You've shrunken everybody
in Bikini Bottom.
你把所有人都缩小了
在比基尼底部。
You've got to go to Mermaidman.
你一定要去看美人鱼。
Oh, Squidward,
he'll be so disappointed!
哦，章鱼哥，
他会很失望的！
Well, you can't
leave us small forever.
好吧，你不能
让我们永远渺小。
You don't understand!
你不明白！
SpongeBob...
海绵宝宝...
You need to admit your mistake.
你需要承认你的错误。
Mom?
妈妈？
Your mother's right, son.
你妈妈是对的，儿子。
Mermaidman will understand.
美人鱼会明白的。
You're Mermaidman, you old coot!
你是美人鱼，你这个老笨蛋！
Oh, yeah.
哦，是的。
Mermaidman?
美人鱼？
I'm so sorry.
我很抱歉。
It's just that
I'm such a big fan,
只是这样
我真是个超级粉丝
and your belt... and...
还有你的腰带……还有……
Aw, don't worry, son.
噢，别担心，儿子。
I understand.
我明白。
Why, I remember back when
I first used the belt,
为什么，我记得那时
我第一次用的是腰带
the year was nineteen,
aught, eleventy-twelve.
那年十九岁，
哦，十一点十二点。
Why, I believe
the president then was...
为什么，我相信
当时的总统是...
Just tell him
how to un-shrink us!
只要告诉他
如何让我们不再缩小！
Oh, yes, the un-shrink ray.
哦，是的，未收缩射线。
Let's see, uh... uh...
让我们看看，呃……呃……
Did you set it to wumbo?
你把它设置为wumbo了吗？
What?
什么？
Get SpongeBob!
获取海绵宝宝！
Now I have to drive five miles
现在我必须开车五英里
to go to the bathroom...
去洗手间...
In my own home!
在我自己家里！
And I need an elevator
我需要一部电梯
to climb one stair!
爬一层楼梯！
We've been shrinking
我们一直在缩小
for years!
多年来！
But this is ridiculous.
但这是荒谬的。
Everything's too big!
一切都太大了！
I've got it.
我明白了。
Ta-da!
哒哒！
Since I couldn't make you big,
I made the city small.
既然我不能让你变得伟大，
我把城市变小了。
And now only
one more thing to shrink.
而现在只有
还有一件事要缩小。
Cheese!
奶酪！
I guess this is okay.
我想这还可以。
Yeah, what's the difference?
是啊，有什么区别？
Good idea, SpongeBob.
好主意，海绵宝宝。
Well, it's great to be back!
嗯，很高兴回来！
Huh?
啊？
Don't worry, Mrs. Puff,
this is the one.
别担心，泡芙女士，
就是这个。
SpongeBob, think, think!
海绵宝宝，想一想，想一想！
Turn that way, turn that way!
往这边转，往那边转！
No, turn that way, left, left!
不，往那边转，左转，左转！
I can do this, Mrs. Puff.
我能做到，帕芙女士。
I can do it, I can do it.
我能做到，我能做到。
The driving test is over,
SpongeBob!
驾照考试结束了
海绵宝宝！
Stop the boat!
停船吧！
Wait, I can do this, Mrs. Puff.
等等，我能做到，帕芙女士。
I can do this.
我可以做到这一点。
Oh!
哦！
The road, SpongeBob!
路上，海绵宝宝！
Get back on the road!
回到路上吧！
Got to pass the test!
Got to pass!
一定要通过考试！
一定要通过！
Hey! What do you got
against the melons?!
嘿！你有什么
反对瓜？！
Look out!
当心！
This must be
the night-driving test.
这必须是
夜间驾驶测试。
We're going to straighten
you out!
我们要矫正
你出去！
This'll fix you!
这会解决你的问题！
Now let's get that one!
现在让我们得到那个！
Barnacles!
Did you see that?
藤壶！
你看到了吗？
Yeah! That guy had
no front license plate!
是的！那家伙有
没有前车牌！
Let's get him.
我们来抓住他吧。
Hey, look at all those police.
嘿，看看那些警察。
I wonder if
the president's in town.
我想知道是否
总统在城里。
Look out!
当心！
It is with great pride
这是非常自豪的
that I officially open
this unfinished bridge!
我正式开放
这座未完工的桥！
Where did I go wrong?
我哪里做错了？
With the opening
of my new boating school,
随着开幕
我的新划船学校，
I pledge that as long as
a student is willing to learn,
我保证只要
一个学生愿意学习，
I shall never give up.
我永远不会放弃。
Hi, I'm SpongeBob SquarePants!
大家好，我是海绵宝宝！
Hurry up with that truckload
of fruit punch!
水果潘趣酒！
The seniors are getting cranky.
前辈们越来越暴躁了。
Alive!
活！
I'm alive!
我还活着！
Oh, thank Neptune, I'm still...
哦，谢谢海王星，我仍然...
All right, seniors,
let's open these windows
好吧，前辈们，
让我们打开这些窗户
so the world can see
your nice white clothes.
让世界可以看到
你漂亮的白衣服。
♪ Gonna be a surfin'...
♪ 要去冲浪...
♪ Surfin'
♪ 冲浪
♪ Surfin', it's gonna...
♪ 冲浪，它会...
It's finally finished!
终于完成了！
A memoir of my life,
written in red ink.
我一生的回忆录，
用红墨水写的。
Oh, barnacles!
哦，藤壶！
SpongeBob, are you okay?
海绵宝宝，你还好吗？
That depends.
这要看情况。
Did I pass?
我通过了吗？
Freeze!
冻结！
You're under arrest.
你被捕了。
Hold it.
握住它。
You can't arrest him.
你不能逮捕他。
He's just a student driver.
他只是一名学生司机。
We're not talking about him.
我们不是在谈论他。
But I don't belong here!
但我不属于这里！
It's all a big mistake.
这都是一个大错误。
Yeah, I don't belong here,
either.
是的，我不属于这里，
要么。
Me, too. I'm innocent.
我也是。我是无辜的。
I belong here!
我属于这里！
Okay, you can do this, Puff.
好吧，你可以做到的，普夫。
You can get through this
without losing your sanity.
你可以渡过这个难关
而又不会失去理智。
Oh, that's a road we don't want
to go down again.
哦，那是一条我们不想要的路
再次下降。
Positives!
积极的一面！
Think of the positives.
想想积极的一面。
Let's see...
让我们来看看...
I've got no more papers
to grade.
我没有更多的文件了
来评分。
Yeah!
是的！
In... in fact, no more work.
事实上……没有更多的工作了。
No more boating school classes.
不再有划船学校课程。
No more driving.
不再开车了。
No more SpongeBob!
不再有海绵宝宝了！
No more phone solicitors.
不再有电话律师。
No more SpongeBob.
不再有海绵宝宝了。
No more company potlucks.
不再有公司聚餐了。
No more SpongeBob.
不再有海绵宝宝了。
No more road rage.
不再有路怒症。
No more SpongeBob.
不再有海绵宝宝了。
No more insurance payments.
不再需要支付保险费。
No more SpongeBob.
不再有海绵宝宝了。
No more SpongeBob!
不再有海绵宝宝了！
No more SpongeBob...!!
不再有海绵宝宝了...!!
I think I'm going
to likethis place.
我想我要去
喜欢这个地方。
Class just isn't the same
只是班级不一样
without Mrs. Puff.
没有帕夫夫人。
Just the thought of her,
alone and afraid in jail...
光是想到她，
在监狱里孤独又害怕……
It makes me think about her
being alone and afraid in jail.
这让我想起她
在监狱里感到孤独和恐惧。
I don't know how
she's going to survive.
我不知道怎么办
她会活下去。
♪ Smelling the pretty roses.
♪ 闻着美丽的玫瑰花香。
♪ Happiness is just
two kinds of ice cream. ♪
♪ 幸福只是
两种冰淇淋。 ♪
Oh, that poor woman.
哦，那个可怜的女人。
And it's all my fault.
这都是我的错。
Maybe if I go talk to Patrick,
he can ease my guilt.
也许如果我去和帕特里克谈谈
他可以减轻我的负罪感。
Well, it sounds like
it's all your fault.
嗯，听起来像
都是你的错。
Oh, you're right.
哦，你是对的。
Mrs. Puff's in jail,
and it's all because of me.
普芙夫人入狱了
这都是因为我。
I'm such a barnacle-head.
我真是个藤壶头。
Poor Mrs. Puff.
可怜的普芙夫人。
I know! I got to get her out.
我知道！我得把她救出来。
But to get her outof jail,
first we got to get injail.
但为了让她出狱
首先我们得被监禁。
How we going to do that?
我们要怎么做呢？
All right, put the money
in the bag!
好吧，把钱投进去
在袋子里！
Put it in!
放进去！
Um, you're facing
the wrong way, sir.
嗯，你面临着
方式错误，先生。
All right,
好的，
give me the money!
给我钱！
Will that be from your savings
这是你的积蓄吗
or your checking account, sir?
或者你的支票账户，先生？
Uh, savings.
呃，储蓄。
May I please see
some identification?
我可以看看吗
一些身份证明？
Sure. There you go.
当然。就这样吧。
Thank you.
谢谢。
Sir, we are showing a balance
先生，我们正在表现出平衡
of zero dollars and zero cents
零美元零美分
for both of your accounts.
对于您的两个帐户。
Oh.
哦。
Next!
下一个！
That went better than expected.
这比预期的要好。
Yeah, I didn't think we'd get
Mrs. Puff out of jail this fast.
是的，我没想到我们会得到
普夫夫人这么快就出狱了。
Don't worry, Patrick,
we'll get into jail this time.
别担心，帕特里克，
这次我们会进监狱的。
Hey, there's a couple.
嘿，有一对。
Put your back in it, girls!
女孩们，把你的背部放回去吧！
Look, Patrick, there she is.
看，帕特里克，她在那儿。
Mrs. Puff, wait!
泡芙太太，等等！
It's us... SpongeBob and Patrick.
是我们……海绵宝宝和帕特里克。
That's funny.
那很好笑。
For a second, I thought
that yellow rock talked to me,
有那么一瞬间，我想
那块黄色的岩石对我说话，
and its voice
sounded a lot like...
和它的声音
听起来很像……
SpongeBob.
It's me, SpongeBob.
海绵宝宝。
是我，海绵宝宝。
We're going to bust you
out of here.
我们要打败你
离开这里。
Come on, Mrs. Puff!
来吧，泡芙夫人！
It's you!
是你！
What are you doing here?
你在这里做什么？
Why did you follow me in here?
你为什么跟着我来这里？
Why?
为什么？
All right,
Mrs. Puff.
好吧，
泡芙女士。
It looks like
this heat's gone
to your head.
看起来像
这热气消失了
到你的头上。
If you're going to talk
to rocks,
如果你要说话
到岩石，
it's time for you
to go on kitchen duty.
你的时间到了
去厨房值班。
Yes!
是的！
It... it must be the heat.
这……一定是天气太热了。
Yes!
是的！
Darn it!
该死的！
Okay, Patrick,
let's get out of here!
好吧，帕特里克，
我们离开这里吧！
No, wait!
不，等等！
There goes our deposit
on these costumes.
我们的押金就这样没了
在这些服装上。
There you are!
你在那里！
Hey there, Puff Mama!
嘿，泡芙妈妈！
What's today's grub?
今天的菜是什么？
Hi, Donna.
嗨，唐娜。
It's chili, same as always.
和往常一样，还是辣椒。
Let me get you some.
让我给你拿一些。
Mrs. Puff,
泡芙女士，
it's me, SpongeBob.
是我，海绵宝宝。
When are these horrific
hallucinations going to end?
什么时候有这些可怕的事
幻觉会结束吗？
No, it's really me!
不，真的是我！
I brought Patrick along, too!
我也把帕特里克也带来了！
Hi.
你好。
Why?!
为什么？！
Because we're going
to set you free!
因为我们要去
让你自由！
No, I mean, why'd you bring him?
不，我是说，你为什么带他来？
He likes chili.
他喜欢辣椒。
Now, quick, get in
before someone sees!
现在，快点，进去吧
在有人看到之前！
SpongeBob, I am not
going with you.
海绵宝宝，我不是
和你一起去。
That's a good one,
Mrs. Puff.
这是一个很好的，
泡芙女士。
Now hop in, come on.
现在跳进去，来吧。
SpongeBob, I think she means it.
海绵宝宝，我想她是认真的。
Oh, that's crazy, Patrick.
哦，那太疯狂了，帕特里克。
He's right, SpongeBob.
他是对的，海绵宝宝。
I'm staying.
我留下来。
But why?
但为什么？
I like it here.
我喜欢这里。
These are my people.
这些是我的人。
And besides, if I'm in here,
另外，如果我在这里的话
that means I won't have to deal
with you... you...
这意味着我不必处理
和你...你...
Uranium in the water supply!
供水系统中含有铀！
See? Crystal clear.
看？晶莹剔透。
Ah.
啊。
Excuse us just
one second, Mrs. Puff.
请原谅我们
等一下，普夫夫人。
Patrick, she has lost it!
帕特里克，她已经迷失了！
She's completely
institutionalized.
她完全是
制度化。
She's forgotten what
it's like to live
on the outside...
她忘记了什么
就像活着
在外面...
To not be in prison.
为了不进监狱。
Coming to bed, honey?
亲爱的，要睡觉了吗？
Yes, dear.
是的亲爱的。
We've got to remind
her there is life
other than this.
我们必须提醒
她有生命
除此之外。
Mrs. Puff,
if you come with us,
泡芙女士，
如果你和我们一起去
I'll stay after
school and decorate
the whole classroom!
之后我会留下来
学校和装饰
整个教室！
For the last time, no!
最后一次，不！
I'm not going with you.
我不会和你一起去。
That's final!
这就是最终的结果！
Oh!
哦！
Talking to inanimate objects
again, eh, Puff?
与无生命的物体交谈
又来了，嗯，泡芙？
Get back to your cell.
回到你的牢房。
No more kitchen time for you.
你不再有厨房时间了。
Quick, Mrs. Puff,
hop on.
快点，帕夫夫人，
跳上来。
Guards! Guards!
Come quick!
卫兵！卫兵！
快来吧！
There's a crazed
ex-student of mine
有一个疯狂的
我以前的学生
and his overweight
friend here
to break me out!
和他超重的
朋友在这里
让我出去！
That's just raw material
这只是原材料
used to make coat hangers.
用于制作衣架。
You need some rest.
你需要休息一下。
Psst!
嘘！
Hop in, Mrs. Puff.
上车吧，普芙夫人。
Guards! Guards!
Come look.
卫兵！卫兵！
过来看看。
Whoa!
哇！
They don't pay me enough
to do this job.
他们付给我的钱不够
来做这项工作。
Mrs. Puff, up here!
普芙女士，上来！
Guards!
卫兵！
Guards! They're back!
卫兵！他们回来了！
What's all the hubbub, Puff?
到底是怎么回事啊，泡芙？
They're back!
他们回来了！
Mrs. Puff, it's us!
泡芙女士，是我们！
What the barnacle is going on?
藤壶这是怎么回事？
Get away from me!
离我远点！
Get away!
逃离！
What are you talking
about, Puff?
你在说什么
关于，普夫？
You can't fool me.
你骗不了我的。
You're SpongeBob
and that guy who
likes the chili.
你是海绵宝宝
和那个人
喜欢辣椒。
Let's face it, Puff,
you've gone off
the deep end.
让我们面对现实吧，泡芙，
你走了
深渊。
Get in there, you!
进来吧，你！
You need a nice long stay
in solitary confinement!
你需要一个愉快的长期住宿
单独监禁！
Oh, well...
那好吧...
Let's look
at the positives again.
让我们看看
再次看到积极的一面。
I'm finally away from those two.
我终于远离那两个人了
Yes, all alone
in my nice soft room.
是的，独自一人
在我漂亮柔软的房间里。
Made of sponge.
由海绵制成。
I can pass the test,
Mrs. Puff!
我能通过考试
泡芙太太！
I can pass the test!
我能通过考试！
Freeze!
冻结！
Your joyride's over, punk!
你的欢乐之旅结束了，朋克！
No!
不！
What?
什么？
No, no!
不，不！
What are you doing?
你在干什么？
Help! Help!
帮助！帮助！
No! No! Please!
不！不！请！
I have a snail to feed.
我有一只蜗牛要喂。
I can't go to jail now.
我现在不能进监狱。
This is not a good time.
现在不是一个好时机。
No, please, please,
I'm not a criminal!
不，拜托，拜托，
我不是罪犯！
I can't believe it.
我简直不敢相信。
It was all a dream.
这一切都是一场梦。
I'm not going to jail!
我不会进监狱的！
Why would you go to jail?
你为什么要进监狱？
You already did your time.
你已经尽了你的时间。
Huh?
啊？
Oh, it's just
my imagination again.
哦，这只是
又是我的想象。
So what's for dinner
tonight, Puff Mama,
chili?
那么晚餐吃什么
今晚，泡芙妈妈，
辣椒？
Aw, forget it.
噢，算了。
And NICKELODEON
还有尼克罗迪恩
Captioned by
Media Access Group at WGBH
access.wgbh.org
标题为
WGBH 媒体访问小组
访问.wgbh.org
标题为
WGBH 媒体访问小组
访问.wgbh.org